Rafael Herrera

116 N 69th Ave Yakima, Wa 98908 (509) 731-0922 rafaelherrera731@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Innovative Management Specialist dedicated to boosting all areas of operations and business administration. Multi-talented leader consistently rewarded for success in planning and operational improvements. Experience in staff management procedures positively impacting overall morale and productivity. Hard working individual that has consistently gone above and beyond, working two jobs simultaneously over the course of the past three year, while always exceeding expectations.

Experience

July 2019 - PRESENT

Enterprise for Progress In the Community (EPIC), Yakima - Assistant Center Manager | Migrant Head Start & Head Start

- Performed reviews assessing each employee's performance and developed improvement plans.
- Explained technical information in clear terms to non-technical individuals to promote better understanding.
- Successfully juggled multiple projects simultaneously to aid executive leaders.
- Observed strict security measures to ensure that all information was kept confidential from unauthorized individuals.
- Work directly with Family Advocates and overlook their work through different programs used by the program
- Responsible for final approval on enrolled families and ensuring complete enrollments for all classrooms at the center
- Travel to multiple centers to ensure the program is operating smoothly and supervise
 Family Advocates and their work
- Work in conjunction with ESD105 in order to stay in the parameters of our grant and deliver our community message

June 2010 - Present

St. Jacks Video, Wapato -Clerk 2010-2016 | Manager 2016-2022

- Counted cash in the register drawer at the beginning and end of shift.
- Restocked, arranged and organized merchandise to drive product sales.
- Monitored systems in operation and troubleshoot when necessary
- Keep logs of merchandise and stock items when stock is low
- Deliver exceptional customer service to patrons
- Present a welcoming and warm environment

Education

2012 - 2016

University of Washington - Bachelors of Arts: Political Science

2022 - In Progress

University of Washington - Coding Certification

Skills

Relationship Building Effective Leader Staff Training/Development Conflict Resolution Extremely Organized Strong Verbal Communication Skilled in Microsoft Office Work Site Preparation